Register of Pierre Marie Gallois Speeches and Writings, 1945-1996
Hoover Institution Archives
Pierre Marie Gallois Speeches and Writings,
1945-1996
81098
Gallois, Pierre Marie, 1911-
29 manuscript boxes (12 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Books, articles, and lectures, relating to aviation, nuclear weapons, French defense policy, the Cold War, collective security, and the North Atlantic Treaty Organization.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Access Points
France. Armée de l'air--Officers.; North Atlantic Treaty Organization.; Aeronautics.; Nuclear weapons.; World politics--1945-; France.; France--Military policy.; Nuclear energy.
Biographical Note
1911, June 29 Born in Turino, Italy
World War II Flew in bombers from England
1945 Joined the general staff of the French Air Force Urged upon President De Gaulle the "Force de Frappe," the independent French nuclear deterrent
1957 Retired as Brigadier General from the French Air Force Author, L'Europe au Défi
1958- Consultant, "Société des Avions Marcel Dassault"
1960 Author, Stratégie a l'Ere Nucléaire
1961 Author, L'Alliance Atlantique
1968 Author, Paradoxes de la Paix
1972 Author, L'Europe Change de Maitre
1975 Author, La Grande Berne
1976 Author, L'Adieu aux Armées
1977 Author, Le Renoncement
Series Description
- SPEECHES AND WRITINGS (mainly in French), 1945-1981. (Box Boxes 1-17)
  Articles, books, editorials, essays, interviews, lectures, studies, work notes, arranged chronologically
- SPEECHES AND WRITINGS, 1981-1982. - (Box 18)
  Increment, July 1982
- SPEECHES AND WRITINGS, 1970-1989. (Box Boxes 19-24)
  Increment, February 1989
- SPEECHES AND WRITINGS, 1955-1991. (Box 25)
  Increment, April 1991
- BIOGRAPHICAL FILE, 1991 (Box 25)
Container List
- SPEECHES AND WRITINGS, 1945-1981.
  See also accompanying itemized list
  - 1945-1947 (Box 1)
  - 1947 (Box 2)
  - 1948 (Box 3)
  - 1949 (Box 4)
  - 1950 (Box 5)
  - 1951-1952 (Box 6)
  - 1953-1954 (Box 7)
  - 1955-1957 (Box 8)
  - 1957-1960 (Box 9)
  - 1961-1962 (Box 10)
  - 1962-1963 (Box 11)
  - 1964-1965 (Box 12)
  - 1966-1967 (Box 13)
  - 1968-1970 (Box 14)
  - 1971-1974 (Box 15)
  - 1975-1978 (Box 16)
  - 1978-1981 (Box 17)
- SPEECHES AND WRITINGS, 1981-1982.
  - 1981-1982 (Box 18)
- SPEECHES AND WRITINGS, 1970-1989.
  - 1970-1980 (Box 19)
  - 1981-1983 (Box 20)
  - 1983-1984 (Box 21)
  - 1984-1985 (Box 22)
  - 1985-1986 (Box 23)
  - 1987-1989 (Box 24)
- SPEECHES AND WRITINGS, 1955-1991.
  - 1955-1991 (Box 25)
- BIOGRAPHICAL FILE, 1991.
  - Photographs and magazine article, 1991, on General Gallois' wall painting hobby. In French (Box 25)